Terricka Parker

UX/UI Designer

(410) 302-7991 · terrickaaparker@gmail.com · Baltimore, MD · terrickaparker.com · in/terrickaparker

I am a UX Designer with a focus on ethical, user-centered design. With over 2 years of experience in using qualitative and quantitative data to increase knowledge retention and enhance the experience of users within my classroom, I have a unique understanding of what it means to be empathetic, solve problems, and design for a diverse range of users. I am looking to bring my knowledge of psychology and design to help businesses differentiate themselves, streamline their processes, and increase user retention.

SKILLS

UX Design I Wireframing, Prototyping, Typography, Color Theory, Information Architecture, Interaction Design, Storyboarding, Design Strategy, Strategic Planning

UX Research I User Interviews, Data Collection and Analysis, Usability Testing, Content Inventory, A/B Testing **Tools** I Figma, Miro, Sketch, Trello, Slack, Adobe XD, UserZoom, Optimum Sort, Notion, Marvel, LucidChart

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2U. Student Success Advisor | Lanham. MD

November 2021 - Present

- Efficiently manage user retention by scheduling, coordinating, and conducting phone and Zoom calls with 200 students in six week increments to continuously gauge users' experience and satisfaction with university partner(s), degree programs, and learning management systems.
- Troubleshoot user issues and devise solutions in accordance with university policies, to reduce program abandonment rates and maintain system usability.

Vengage Consulting, UX Design | Atlanta, GA

July 2021 - April 2022

- Engage in all aspects of the user experience (UX) design process including conducting research and diving deep into the client's industry and business challenges at the onset of projects.
- Collaborate with senior designers to reconfigure the user flow and visual design of an education mobile application, allowing users to access their courses 73% faster than before.
- Present findings and recommendations after evaluating user interfaces and administering audits of websites and mobile apps for usability issues.

Upilio, UX Designer | Remote

November 2021

- Designed an intuitive user interface and information architectural system that worked to reduce user task completion time by 68% when onboarding and utilizing in-app features like the foods list and meal plan.
- Executed the end-to-end double diamond process to redesign and create high fidelity clickable prototypes, including
 conducting user research, crafting personas, creating sketches, wireframes, and prototypes, and conducting usability tests.
- Participated in an agile UX process to develop and implement data-driven design decisions and efficiently hand-off prototypes and design systems to developers.

Baltimore City Public Schools, Elementary Certified Teacher | Baltimore, MD

August 2019 - November 2021

- Designed and implemented curriculum based, multi-sensory lesson plans for various users to accommodate varying user needs and learning styles.
- Created and carried out a behavior modification system based on a variety of target personas, increasing behavior scores by an average of 47% week over week.
- Increased 44% of student reading levels by 1 to 1.5 grade levels by Identifying user's individual and collective learning needs and also planning, preparing and delivering instruction designed to increase user engagement and maximize individual learning.
- Developed and executed a five-week curriculum grounded in user research to engage and teach students that have previously failed core content courses, resulting in an 87% pass rate.

UX DESIGN PROJECTS___

_June 2021 - Present

Live Nation | UX Designer | Mobile Application Enhancement and Redesign

- Four-week design sprint resulting in the redesign of a mobile application based on ioS and brand guidelines as well as UX research.
- Created several wireframes and prototypes of varying fidelity using Figma to test assumptions, concepts, and usability.

Headed primary and secondary research to craft personas, sketches, user flows, and interactions.

Local Color Flowers | UX Designer | Full Scale E-commerce Redesign

- Decreased bounce rate by 45% by reconstructing existing navigation design.
- Performed interface design, interaction design, and information design using Figma and Miro to craft a fully responsive e-commerce website.
- Conducted user interviews as well as a competitive and comparative analysis to develop solutions grounded in user research.

Stay In, Dine Out | UX Designer | Food Delivery Application Concept

- Developed a screener survey and comprehensive interview process to ensure that user insights were provided by ideal participants.
- Designed a high fidelity prototype based on results from two rounds of usability tests conducted on sketches and a lo-fi wireframe.
- Crafted a target persona and multiple user flows derived from user insights and feedback.

EDUCATION

General Assembly | Remote

UX Design Immersive

June 2021 - Dec 2021

Full-time immersive program in UX/UI design consisting of 480+ hours of study, practice, professional training, and mentorship. Executed end-to-end UX/UI design processes for six projects from the user research phase through UI design, prototyping, usability testing, iteration, and stakeholder presentation; worked fully remote with teams using Agile methodologies and iterative development.

Johns Hopkins School of Education | Baltimore, MD

Master of Science in Education

May 2021

Williams College | Williamstown, MA

Bachelor of Arts in Political Science, Concentrations in International Relations, Africana Studies, and Justice and Law J

June 2019